

Lalji Patel

Mobile: +91-9958471432 Email: Lalji97patel@Gmail.Com

Address: Sahumai (bichalahla) radhouli kunda pratapgarh Utter Pradesh

(230202)

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Personable and knowledgeable IT support On Linux and Windows base with over 5+ years of experience assisting customers with various hardware and software related issues. Provided in-depth technical support to clients at a Tier 2 level, solving 90% of issues without transferring to Tier 3 support. Seeking to provide expert technical support to enterprise organizations as the L3 tech support engineer at Rose IT Solution.

- An effective communicator with excellent interpersonal and relationship building skills.
- Good communication abilities and interpersonal skills and ready to handle extreme work pressure with quality productivity.
- Friendly with an upbeat attitude
- Well working knowledge in Linux and Unix Environment as well windows os.
- Supportable 24/7 from home
- Remotely working by SSH and TeamViewer and other tools.

PERSONAL DETAILS

Date of Birth: 14th September 1994. **Father's Name:** Mr. Maiku lal Patel

Permanent Address: Sahumai (bichalahla) radhouli kunda pratapgarh Utter Pradesh (230202)

Gender: Male Nationality: Indian

Pan card no.: AVVPJ0433G Passport no.: M0224446 Marital Status: Single

Languages Known: English, Hindi

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Programming Languages: Shell scripting (base), Python, Django, React

Software/Databases: Mail, VNC, RDP, Lync, TeamViewer, Outlook, MS Word, Excel, SQL,

MYSQL, Teams, VScode, IDLE

Operating Systems: Linux/Unix, Any flavor of Linux/Unix such as RHEL, SuSE Linux, Debian

Ubuntu, fedora, Kali Linux, backtrack Linux, cents, Unix etc., Redhat 6,7/Linux/Unix ,Windows, XP/Vista/7/8,Ubuntu,Backtrack Linux, Debian

OS well known

Hardware: PC Assemble and Repair, Replace the part of Systems

Networking: Network Troubleshooting and Fix issue, Assigning IP Address, Defining

their Class, FTP, NFS, HTTP, DNS, CUPS, DHCP, SAMBA, NFS, SSH,

Telnet

Web Applications: Apache, Tomcat, Wireshark

Others: Well Working Experience on All the Flavor of the Linux and ready to accept

Challenge Related to Linux Issue and Related to Services.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Looking to change my job due to new challenging task in IT industries.

ROSE IT SOLUTION PVT. LTD., Delhi, INDIA

Admin Associate

May 2019 - Present

May 2015 - Mar 2017

Rose IT Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (RITS), a wholly owned subsidiary of Rose International, is located in New Delhi, India. The center was founded in early 2002, and is certified CMM Level 3 by the Software Engineering Institute (SEI). RITS works with Rose International to offer complete information technology solutions that focus on delivering cost effective, efficient and reliable results. RITS understands the processes and technologies that are required to successfully meet the business challenges of today.

Role & Responsibilities:-

- OS installation and Upgrading Latest OS with Latest software.
- Remote Desktop by VNC and Teams.
- Multiple Task at the same time.
- Actively coordinate with international Client.
- Working on Outlook and configure and mail backup.
- Network and system troubleshooting and printer installing.
- Mail configuration like outlook and thunderbird.
- Data Uploading.
- Troubleshooting in system like Ubuntu and Linux.
- Supportable OS like Linux and Ubuntu, Centos etc.
- Check Server Health.
- Printer's configuration and installing.
- Take Data Backup and Data Migrate over Network.
- Automation for Data backup and refresh service.
- Full time frontend and backend support for server issues.
- Prepare daily and weekly report on MS Office.
- Attend the international Call and Mail.
- Using chatting tool teams and any desk remote tool.

Technologies: Lync, TeamViewer, Outlook, Teams, Linux and Ubuntu, Centos

"GAP between Mar 2017 - Apr 2019 Due to a Family Issue."

SHOT FORMATS DIGITAL PRODUCTION PVT. LTD Noida & Mumbai

IT Support Engineer

Shot Formats Digital Production Pvt. Ltd. Is a new media company that develops innovative digital platforms, to service? It is a mobile Value Added Services (VAS) company having priorities to create and deploy VAS Solution and applications for media houses, film companies etc.

Role & Responsibilities:-

- Monitoring VAS Service logs.
- Resolving errors occurring in the services.
- Handling Operator issues and resolving them.
- Daily Checkup of all servers.
- Handling Customers issues and resolving them.
- Involved in the implementation of the overall IT facility of the organization.
- Software, Hardware, Database and Network related facility.
- Troubleshoot the problem.
- Monitor the network and check the internet connection is available or not.
- Configure or control all the network & Assemble the Computer.
- Provide the valuable software to the employees whenever they require.
- Manage the Linux network, Configure OS TICKET for a Ticket support.
- Assigning the role and provide the permission to user account.
- Monitoring Network Traffic and providing the user web access for unrestricted sites.
- Managing the Wireless Networking System.
- Configuring and Troubleshooting of Outlook express and MS Office Outlook.
- Maintaining Backup of System data and Software's data.

- Handling Internet Lease Line.
- Troubleshooting/Installing OS.
- Managed 100 computers in Domain and Workgroup Workstation including Desktops/Laptops.

Technologies: VAS, Linux, Networking, MS Office Outlook, Lease Line, Troubleshooting

TRIDENT ENTERPRISES Allahabad U.P.

Sep 2012 - Dec 2013

Service Engineer

- Create users and provide them service.
- Changing the part of Desktop Like hard drive, ram, motherboard etc.
- Configure the thin client.
- Check the network connectivity and fix network issue.
- · Maintain reports monthly and weekly.
- OS (Linux) installation Like Ubuntu 12.04 and RHEL 5.4 and Centos etc. Via text mode and GUI.

Technologies: Ubuntu 12.04 and RHEL 5.4 and Centos

LINUX PLATFORM

- Installation/upgrade of Red Hat Linux/Unix (RHEL-6 RHEL-7) server through Network PXE.
- Installation, FTP, NFS, HTTP.
- Installation and configuration of Squid Proxy Server.
- Configuration & troubleshooting DNS server.
- Can configure yum repository and can install, remove, update and query packages using RPM.
- Configuration & troubleshooting Apache Web Server.
- Configuring Printing (CUPS) Services.
- Upgrading LINUX & Other Applications (RPM).
- Creating users and groups in command mode and GUI.
- Implementing file permissions for the users and groups.
- Mail servers send mail, Postfix.
- DHCP server configuration.
- Troubleshooting of User's issues related to Hardware/ Operating Systems/ Software's and Local Area Network.
- Can configure and manage Logical Volume.
- Configuring SAMBA Server, NFS Server.
- PXE server installation and configuration.
- Partition creation in command mode and GUI mounting permanent.
- Remote Administration of LINUX/UNIX using VNC, SSH.
- Troubleshooting of User's issues related to Hardware/ Operating Systems/ Software's and Local Area Network On Linux/Unix.
- Working on latest OS of Debian like Ubuntu 20.04 lts and Kali Linux.

CEH PLATFORM

- Kali Linux installation, Update & Upgrade.
- Penetration Testing & Ethical hacking
- Information Gathering.
- Scanning and Enumeration.
- Vulnerability Assessment.
- Metasploit and Exploitation.
- Post Exploitation.
- Password Cracking.
- Web Application Testing.
- Social Engineering.
- Wireless Testing.
- Malware.
- Deep Web, Dark Web & Tor

Document and Reporting.

PYTHON & DJANGO PLATFORM

- Writing and Executing Python Program.
- Python Language Fundamentals.
- Python Conditional Statements.
- Looping Statements, Standard Data Types, String Handling.
- Python List, Python Tuple, Set, Dictionary, Functions.
- Namespaces & Scopes, Modules & Packages, Object Oriented Programming.
- Exception Handling, Python Database Connectivity.
- GUI Programming, Multi-Threading Programming, Socket Programming, Regular Expressions(Regex).

Projects

- Top N Words in a Text File.
- Bank Account Automation.
- You tube Video Downloader.
- Expense Tracker.

Django

- Miscellaneous.
- Developing Web Services (APIs).
- Django User Authentication.
- Django Middleware.
- Django State and Session Handling, Django Admin Interface.
- Django Models (ORM), Understanding Django Forms, Django Templates (Presentation Logic).
- Understanding Django Project, Web Application Programming.

Projects

- City Search.
- E-commerce web application.
- Blogging web application.
- Vehicle Pooling.
- Project Deployment (Making Project LIVE).
- Understanding domain and hosting.
- Deploy the project.

EDUCATION

B.Com

Dr. Ram Manohar Lohiya Avadh University (University) of Faizabad in 2014

Intermediate

U.P board in 2011

High school

U.P board in 2009

CERTIFICATIONS

REDHAT

RHCE- Certified and Certificate number is: 140-210-336 RHCSA- Certified and Certificate number is: 140-210-310

ADDITIONAL TRAINING

Redhat

3 Months Training on Red Hat Linux in Network Nuts (South Ex. New Delhi). From Aug 2014 - Oct 2014

CEH

Cybertron Network Solutions, Laxmi Nagar, New Delhi, Delhi 110092

Python & Django, React

Ducat, Noida Utter Pradesh

Strength

Team Player with strong work ethic, committed to hard work.

A quick learner with abilities to work in a team environment and work under strict deadlines.

Interests

Talking in English and listening songs. Learning new tools on Linux.

DECLARATION

I hereby declare that the information given above is true to the best of my knowledge and belief and can be supported with reliable documents when needed.

Date...... (Lalji Patel)